<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[The AlvoRithm]]></title><description><![CDATA[The AlvoRithm]]></description><link>http://alvorithm.com/</link><image><url>http://alvorithm.com/favicon.png</url><title>The AlvoRithm</title><link>http://alvorithm.com/</link></image><generator>Ghost 5.87</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:54:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://alvorithm.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Quitting to Start: Embracing Change and Deep Diving into AI]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Picture this:&#xA0;</strong>there I was, comfortably nestled in an engineering management role at Cisco, a legendary tech giant with an amazing benefits and compensation package. Life was good, right? Well, it was... but if you&apos;re anything like me, an engineer at heart, something was missing over time.</p>]]></description><link>http://alvorithm.com/quitting-to-start-embracing-change-and-deep-diving-into-ai/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">66985ac803a5506d375c2740</guid><category><![CDATA[Career]]></category><category><![CDATA[AI]]></category><category><![CDATA[Personal Blog]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alvin S. Wong]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://alvorithm.com/content/images/2024/07/2023-Dec-26---Chan-Extended-Family-Christmas-Party-38.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://alvorithm.com/content/images/2024/07/2023-Dec-26---Chan-Extended-Family-Christmas-Party-38.jpg" alt="Quitting to Start: Embracing Change and Deep Diving into AI"><p><strong>Picture this:&#xA0;</strong>there I was, comfortably nestled in an engineering management role at Cisco, a legendary tech giant with an amazing benefits and compensation package. Life was good, right? Well, it was... but if you&apos;re anything like me, an engineer at heart, something was missing over time. That spark, that fire in my belly that made me fall in love with tech 20+ years ago.</p><p>So, I did what any rational person would do.&#xA0;<strong>I quit my job. &#x1F605;</strong></p><p>Crazy? Maybe. Exciting? Absolutely! &#xA0;<strong>Let&apos;s talk about it...</strong></p><p><em>(Thanks for reading! &#x1F60A; I share all this openly with the hope that it helps&#xA0;<strong>you</strong>&#xA0;with your life and pursuits, both in work and your passion for your craft. May it offer at least one tech industry colleague&apos;s experience for your consideration.)</em></p><h4 id="a-leap-of-faith">A Leap of Faith</h4><p>I worked at Cisco for about a decade since the acquisition of OpenDNS in 2015 - the hot security startup I had joined back then. Over the years, I gathered a ton of experience across several teams and roles, including Security Engineer, Network Engineer, Software Engineer, Technical Lead, and Senior Tech Lead.</p><p>As I gained more seniority and leadership experience, I naturally moved into leadership roles and became part of the senior levels of Engineering Management, stepping in wherever our business needed me. I was fortunate to join, start, hire, and lead teams, working with a ton of smart, awesome people, and together we delivered on some impactful projects.</p><p>My career in a big tech giant was going well, and the momentum of the business cycles was fulfilling. But deep down, perhaps like some of you in the industry reading this blog, I gradually found it more difficult to extricate myself from necessary but lengthy corporate processes, meetings, and management tasks. I longed to spend personal time on immediate hands-on exploration and building things directly.</p><p>I loved my team, and fostering their teamwork and growth is something I will cherish forever. However, what was best for the team often trumped my desire to spend time coding and building directly.&#xA0;<strong>As it should, and I would pick them over me any day of the week.</strong></p><p>With my deep passion and obsession with the AI/ML explosion, I came to a realization.&#xA0;<strong>I needed a change to follow my heart and pursue more exploration into AI/ML adoption.</strong>&#xA0;I wanted to learn and develop directly, something I had been obsessed about lately.</p><p>After discussing with my family and ensuring I could survive for several months, I made a hard decision and took a leap of faith.&#xA0;<strong>I decided to swing the pendulum back to being hands-on by taking 3-6 months away from a traditional &quot;day job&quot; to learn everything I could about AI/ML.</strong>&#xA0;I aimed to understand how to work with it, how to code with it, how to develop content and business strategies with it, and ultimately how to build a startup with it.</p><p>Yes, call me crazy &#x1F61C;, but I&apos;m simultaneously juggling studying, coding, and building while maintaining my business and leadership skills through a solo-preneur startup project.&#xA0;<strong>Let&apos;s see how far and fast AI can take us as a force multiplier!</strong>&#xA0;&#x1F680;</p><p><em>(Spoiler alert:&#xA0;<strong>It&apos;s only been 3 weeks, and I&apos;ve never been more productive, excited, and focused.</strong>&#xA0;Working long and hard with new tooling and tech, co-developing and brainstorming with LLMs, this is a huge upgrade in personal satisfaction. Life&apos;s good &#x1F60A;.)</em></p><h4 id="discovering-alvorithm">Discovering AlvoRithm</h4><p>During this transition, I felt I needed a new face and brand to reinvent myself. &#xA0;I&apos;ve decided on the&#xA0;<strong>AlvoRithm</strong>. &#xA0;</p><p>AlvoRithm will be a personal brand dedicated to sharing my journey, insights, and discoveries in AI. It&#x2019;s a play on words, combining my passions for music production, video content creation, and more. AlvoRithm is not just a platform for documenting my experiences; it&#x2019;s also a space where I aim to inspire and educate others who are passionate about technology and creativity.</p><p><strong>AlvoRithm&apos;s mission is to bridge the gap between AI theory and practical application, providing valuable insights to software developers, tech professionals, aspiring engineers, and anyone interested in the future of technology.</strong>&#xA0;Through blogs, vlogs, and social media, I share weekly updates in a Sprint retrospective style, highlighting what went well, what I learned, and areas for improvement.</p><h4 id="learning-and-growing">Learning and Growing</h4><p>My journey into AI has been incredibly enriching over the last three weeks. I&apos;m currently diving deep into Deep Learning Specialization courses from Coursera with Andrew Ng from Stanford University. These courses provide a solid theoretical foundation and practical skills essential for navigating the AI landscape.</p><p>In parallel, I&apos;m working on a startup idea that leverages AI to create innovative solutions. This hands-on project allows me to experiment with the latest LLM models, cutting-edge techniques, and applications for software development. It&apos;s an exhilarating process that combines creativity, technical expertise, and a passion for problem-solving.</p><h4 id="sharing-knowledge">Sharing Knowledge</h4><p>One of my core beliefs is that knowledge should be shared. Through AlvoRithm, I aim to distill complex AI concepts into easily digestible content. My goal is to save you time and provide you with the most valuable insights from a seasoned tech industry professional.</p><p>I can start with going over what I believe every tech enthusiast should explore in order:</p><ol><li><strong>Conversational AI</strong>: Engage with chat models like OpenAI&apos;s GPT-4 or Anthropic&apos;s Claude.</li><li><strong>Image Generation</strong>: Experiment with tools like DALL-E, Midjourney for generating images or equivalent.</li><li><strong>Foundational Concepts</strong>: Understand key AI terms and concepts (e.g. LLMs, Supervised, Unsupervised, Parameters, Quantization, Fine-Tuning, context-windows, temperature, RAG, multi-modal, agents.</li><li><strong>Coding Assistants</strong>: Integrate the latest code workflow enhancing tools (e.g. Github CoPilot, Agentic Frameworks like Crew.ai or Autogen).</li><li><strong>Local Hosting</strong>: Explore local LLM hosting alternatives and open-source models.</li><li><strong>Popular Models</strong>: Try out various open-source models (e.g. LLaMA 3, Mistral, Gemma 2) vs paid models (ChatGPT, Claude)</li></ol><h4 id="looking-ahead">Looking Ahead</h4><p>As I continue this exciting journey, I&apos;m committed to launching at least one new startup around September, centered around an AI-based application I&apos;m passionate about and I&apos;ll be using AI itself to help accelerate and implement the service.&#xA0;</p><p>AlvoRithm will be the hub where I share every step of this journey, offering insights, lessons learned, and inspiration to my audience.</p><h4 id="call-to-action">Call to Action</h4><p>If you&apos;re intrigued by my journey and want to stay updated and keep in touch on the latest in AI, tech, and creative content, I invite you to follow me:</p><p>- LinkedIn:&#xA0;<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alvinswong/?ref=localhost">https://www.linkedin.com/in/alvinswong/</a></p><p>- YouTube: AlvoRithm - YouTube channel&#xA0;</p><p>- X.com (Twitter) - @theAlvoRithm</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>